nextopia.com 2017-09-29

# Privacy Policy - How Your Information is Used | Nextopia

This Privacy Policy governs the collection, use, disclosure and retention of all Personal Information that you provide to Nextopia Software Corporation. (“Nextopia,” “us” or “we”) via nextopia.com (the “Website”) or that you provide directly or indirectly by other means. This Privacy Policy will help you understand how Nextopia protects, collects, uses and discloses your Personal Information. We may revise this Privacy Policy at any time by updating this page.

**1\. Personal Information**  
Personal Information means information about an identifiable individual. Most Personal Information you provide, directly or indirectly, to Nextopia is provided for the purpose of displaying it on the Website and, as such, is Public Personal Information. Other Personal Information you may provide directly to us for purposes other than displaying it on the Website is Private Personal Information. When you provide Private Personal Information to us, we promise to hold your Private Personal Information confidential and to distribute that information only in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**2\. Nextopia’ Privacy Policy Coverage**  
Nextopia’ Privacy Policy covers Nextopia’ management of Personal Information that Nextopia collects when you are on the Website, and when you use Nextopia’ services, and to Public Personal Information that Nextopia collects from third-party websites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies or other entities that Nextopia does not own or control, or to people that Nextopia does not employ or manage. Any Personal Information you supply, or authorize us, implicitly or explicitly, to supply to any third parties, is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties.

**3\. What Information is Collected**  
Nextopia collects Personal Information you provide when you register on the Website and use the Website, such as your name, email address, Website usage data, and similar information that you voluntarily provide to us via the Website. We may also collect Public Personal information, such as your name, gender, goals and relationship status that you make publicly available to us on third-party websites.

**4\. For What Purpose the Information is Collected**  
Nextopia collects your Personal Information to provide the services that we offer. We may also use your Personal Information, if applicable, to verify your identity, to make payments for services, to provide our services or support for our services, to respond to your queries, or to provide you with further information regarding our services. As a user of the Website, you acknowledge and agree that Nextopia may aggregate information about you and your use of the Website with similar information collected from users to enhance and optimize the services provided through the Website. Your general use of the Website may be included in an anonymized fashion in aggregate reports. The purpose of such aggregate reports is to better understand how the Website is used, for marketing and development purposes.

**5\. Use of Cookies**  
Cookies are small text files used by your browser to store information. The purpose of cookies is to enhance your browsing experience by allowing us to tailor our Website and to facilitate the collection of Personal and non-Personal Information. You can configure your web browser to either refuse to accept any cookies or prompt you before a cookie is placed on your computer. Refusal of cookies may, in some cases, prevent you from visiting certain sections of the Website, or from receiving personalized information when visiting the Website. Cookies cannot be used by Nextopia to retrieve any Personal Information about you unless you have previously registered with the Website. Nextopia does not and cannot use cookies to retrieve Personal Information about you from your computer unless such information was knowingly and willingly provided by you.

**6\. Targeted Advertising and Other Content**  
When you are using the Website, Nextopia may, from time to time, display to you advertising and promotional content that it determines may be of interest to you based on information you have provided to Nextopia. However, we will not provide any of your Private Personal Information to any third party without your express consent.

**7\. Data Retention**  
We will only retain your Personal Information as long as it continues to serve the purposes identified above.  
Upon your request, made via the Website, we will permanently delete all your Personal Information that we have collected. The length of time we keep your Personal Information will vary depending on your use of our services and the nature of the Private Personal Information. When your information is no longer required for the purposes set out above, Nextopia will delete any Private Personal Information that could identify you. Nextopia may retain non-identifying information such as Website usage statistics.

**8\. Disclosure of Personal Information**  
Your Private Personal Information will not be disclosed or shared with any third party unless:

  * Nextopia obtains your express consent to share such information;
  * We are reasonably required to disclose the information to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors or service providers in order to provide our services;
  * Nextopia needs to share the information with entities (partners) who work on behalf of Nextopia to provide a product or service to you. Whenever we share your Private Personal Information with these partners, they work under confidentiality agreements and are subject to this Privacy Policy. Unless we expressly tell you differently, these partners do not have any right to use the Private Personal Information we provide to them beyond what is necessary to provide the services;
  * Nextopia is required by law, regulation, court order, warrant, subpoena, or other lawful request or demand by a governmental or law enforcement authority to disclose or share your Private Personal Information;
  * Nextopia, in its sole judgment, believes it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, fraud, fraudulent misrepresentation, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required or permitted by law; or
  * Nextopia finds that your actions on our Website violate your agreement with Nextopia, as defined in the Terms of Service, and disclosure is required to enforce our rights.

**9\. How the Information is Protected**  
Nextopia limits access to your Private Personal Information and stores it securely. Nextopia employs physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect our systems and all Private Personal Information under our control against unauthorized use and access. However, no method of transmitting or storing data is completely secure.  
In addition to the security mechanisms we use to protect your information, we have strict security standards and practices to protect our computer systems and your Private Personal Information from unauthorized use or access. Nextopia insists that its employees who have access to your Private Personal Information are made aware of how to keep it confidential. Nextopia ensures that its employees understand that maintaining confidentiality is a condition of employment. Access to your Private Personal Information is only given to those who require it to provide services, or where permitted or required by law.

**10\. Storage Location of Private Personal Information**  
Nextopia and its affiliates, and other third parties to whom we disclose information under this Privacy Policy, may perform activities such as data storage and processing in various countries. As a result, your Private Personal Information may be securely used, stored or accessed in such countries and may be subject to the laws of those countries. For example, information may be disclosed in response to valid demands or requests from government authorities, courts, or law enforcement in these countries.

**11\. Questions**  
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or require additional information about our practices, please contact our Privacy Officer via the Contact page on the Website.
